《大独裁者》
在世界大战末期 Tomainia已经无力支撑这场战争
At the end of the World War Tomainia weakened.
同时 Tomainia国内爆发了革命 外交官们提出结束战争
Revolution had broken out, her diplomats sued for peace
而此时Tomainia的军队仍在继续战斗
while Tomainia's army fought on,
他们相信自己的战争机器能够摧毁敌人的防线
confident its war machine would smash the enemy's lines.
巨型Bertha 射程100英里
Big Bertha, able to fire 100 miles,
这是它在西线战场的处女秀 为的是造成敌人的恐慌
was to make its appearance on the Western Front,and strike terror into the enemy.
它的目标是75英里外的：Notre-Dame大教堂
75 miles away was her target: The cathedral of Notre-Dame.
方位: 95,452
Range: 95,452.
预备!
Stand clear!
开炮!
Fire!
回到你的炮手位上去!
Stand by your trigger!
修正方位：95 455
Range correction: 95,455.
装弹完毕
Breach secured.
预备!
Stand clear.
准备...开炮!
Ready... Fire!
炮弹有问题 我们去检查一下 走
Defective shell. We'll examine it.Go.
去检查炮弹引信
Check the fuse.
是 长官
Yes,sir.
是的 去检查引信
Yes, the fuse.
小心!快跑!
Look out! Run!
那是怎么回事?
What's that?
- 空袭 - 冲着巨型Bertha大炮来的
- Air raid. - After Big Bertha.
防空机枪!
The anti-aircraft gun!
快到机枪那里去!
To the gun!
你疯了吗?
Have you gone crazy?
下来!
Come down!
你到底在干什么?!你疯了吗?!
What do you think you're doing? Have you gone crazy?
长官 敌人攻过来了 所有人准备战斗
Sir, the enemy have broken through. Every man to the front.
全体集合!
Muster the gun crew!
拿上你的手榴弹 士兵
Get your hand grenades, soldiers.
你的手榴弹呢?
Where's your hand grenade?
给他一个
Give him one.
不许停下 跟上 快!
Keep moving. Come along, hurry up!
抱歉 这个该怎么用...
Pardon me, but to work this...
拉掉保险栓 数到十 然后扔出去!
Pull the pin, count to ten and throw it!
扔手榴弹!
Let them have it!
喂 过来
Hey,come here.
现在没时间挠痒痒
This is no time to scratch.
给我站好
Pull yourself together.
拿上
Take this.
前进!
Forward!
集合!
Fall in!
嘿 你们 过来!
Hey you, come on!
立正!
Order arms!
准备战斗
Prepare to attack.
前进!
Forward!
上尉?
Captain?
你们在这儿啊
There you are.
是敌人!快 抓住他!
The enemy! Come on, let's get him!
我能进来吗 长官?
May I come in, sir?
- 谁? - 自己人
- Who is it? - Friend.
- 你是哪个部队的? - 第21炮兵师 长官
- What division? - 21st artillery, sir.
拿着这个 继续开火 我一会儿就回来
Take this and keep firing. I'll be back.
同志 救救我!
Comrade! Help!
你怎么了?
What is it?
我累坏了 快 扶我到我的飞机那里去
I'm exhausted. Quick, help me to my plane.
谢谢你 我保证你会为此获得Tomainian十字勋章的
Thank you. I'll see you get the Tomainian Cross for this.
乐意效劳 长官
Only too willing to oblige, sir.
你救了我的命 谢谢你
You saved my life. Thank you
我会把你绑在上边
I'll strap you in.
我一个人不行 你必须得留下来帮我
I can't make it alone. You'll have to stay with me.
你会开飞机吗?
Can you fly?
我试试吧
I can try.
把我的手放到操纵杆上 我已经没力气了
Lift my hand to the stick. I haven't the strength.
拿走那挺枪!
Take charge of that gun!
敌人来了! 快 把我的手放到油门上
The enemy! Quick, lift my hand to the throttle.
让我们耍耍他们!
We'll fool 'em!
抓紧这些急件
Hold on to these dispatches.
如果我们把它们送到Schmelloffel将军那里
If we get them to General Schmelloffel,
Tomainia也许就能取得这场战争的胜利
Tomainia may yet win.
我快要晕过去了
I'm going to faint.
别那样说
Don't say that.
抱歉
Sorry.
我在什么地方?
Where am I?
你不认识我了吗?
Don't you know me?
是的 我现在感觉好多了
Yes, I feel better now.
血液又流回我的大脑了
The blood's returning to my head.
下面的是什么?
What's below?
太阳吗?
The sun?
阳光射向上面
Shining upwards.
奇怪 怎么有汽油味道?
Strange. How's the gas?
我整晚都没睡好
Kept me awake all night.
不 是油箱里的汽油!
No, the gasoline in the tank!
快用光了
Almost empty.
我们一定快到了 现在几点了?
We must be nearly there. What time is it?
差一分正好十二点
Approximately one minute to twelve.
奇怪
Strange.
看起来我们好像违反了万有引力定律
We seem to be defying the laws of gravity.
给我水 快 我快晕过去了
Water. Quick, I'm going to faint.
等一下
Wait a while.
如果你再晕的话 我们就有麻烦了
We'll get into trouble if you faint any more.
坚持住
Just hold it.
我想...我现在...
I think I... Now...
拿着它!
Take it!
有点不大对劲
Something's wrong.
我喝不着
I can't reach it.
全都没了
It's all gone.
出什么事了?
What's the matter?
带子系得太紧了
Belt too tight.
松开它
Loosen it.
我正在试着松开它!
I'm trying to!
我们翻过来了
We're upside down.
我知道!
I know it!
给我操纵杆!
The stick!
办不到
Impossible.
喔 完了 我们没有汽油了
There it goes. We're out of gas.
好吧 我想这下我们完了 要烟吗?
Well, I suppose this is the end. Cigarette?
没有!
Not now!
反正我也不再需要烟了
I shan't need this any more.
现在是几月份?
What month is it?
四月 Tomainia现在是春天
April. Spring in Tomainia.
Hilda会在花园里
Hilda will be in the garden,
照看水仙花
tending the daffodils.
她是多么的爱水仙花啊!
How she loves daffodils!
她因为害怕伤到它们所以从来都不修剪
She'd never cut them for fear of hurting them.
好像修剪水仙花就是在杀生一般
It was like taking a life to cut a daffodil.
我甜美的 端庄的Hilda
Sweet, gentle Hilda.
有一个善良的灵魂
A beautiful soul.
她喜爱动物 还有小孩子
She loved animals, and little children, too.
我们着陆了!急件呢!
We've landed! Dispatches!
同志 你在哪里?
Comrade, where are you?
急件...它们在什么地方?
The dispatches... Where are they?
- 你受伤了没? - 带我去见Schmelloffel将军
- Are you hurt? - Take me to General Schmelloffel.
要是我们不把这些急件送到的话 我们就失败了
If we don't deliver these, we're defeated.
- 战争结束了 - 什么?
- The war's over. - What?
- 我们输了 - 输了... 啊...
- We lost. - Lost...Ah...
停战!
和平!
田布西被威拉特击败!
林白横渡大西洋!
大萧条!
Tomainia发生暴动!
希克勒掌权了
Hynkel takes power.
这名犹太士兵患了失忆症并在医院里待了好几年
The Jewish soldier suffered a loss of memory and remained in hospital for years,
完全不知道Tomainia已经发生了怎样的变化
ignorant of the change in Tomainia.
希克勒以铁腕手段统治着这个国家
Hynkel ruled the nation with an iron fist.
在双X徽章下 自由被任意践踏
Under the double-cross emblem liberty was banished.
只有希克勒一个人说了算
Only the voice of Hynkel was heard.
阿道诺·希克勒刚才说的是：
Adenoid Hynkel said,
"Tomainia曾经被打败但是今天已经崛起了"
"Tomainia was down but today has risen. "
"民主是芳香诱人的"
"Democracy is fragrant. "
"自由是可憎的"
"Liberty is odious. "
"言论自由是令人讨厌的"
"Freedom of speech is objectionable. "
"Tomainia如今有最强大的陆军"
"Tomainia has the greatest army. "
"最强大的海军"
"The greatest navy. "
"但为了维持我们强大的军队 我们必须做出牺牲"
"But to remain great we must sacrifice. "
我们必须勒紧我们的裤腰带（皮带）
"We must tighten our belts. "
他正同国防部长 陆军元帅Herring将军谈话
He now speaks to Field Marshal Herring, Minister of War.
接下来是内政部长 Garbitsch先生
Now Herr Garbitsch, Minister of the Interior.
他想起了自己早期
He remembers his early struggles,
与两位忠诚的同志并肩战斗的日子
shared by his two loyal comrades.
刚才那些话是针对犹太人说的
A reference to the Jewish people.
元首刚才的感叹向世界表明：
The Phooey remarks that for the world
他的内心期望和平
he has peace in his heart.
因设备检修我们中断播出
We now pause for station identification.
这是由pari-Mutual广播网 为您播出的
This is the Pari-Mutual network, bringing you
希克勒对双X徽章照耀下的子民们的演说
Hynkel's address to the children of the double-cross.
同声口译
The interpreter
是由希克勒的私人翻译
is Hynkel's personal translator,
依照一份准备好的稿子念出来的
reading from a prepared manuscript.
请不要走开 我们会接着为您作实况报导 前进 Tomainia
Stand by for further commentary. Go ahead, Tomainia.
阁下他准备走下讲台了
His Excellency is about to descend the stairs.
阁下 您没受伤吧?
Your Excellency, are you hurt?
你乘另一辆车
Ride in the other car.
阁下他
His Excellency
看上去非常高兴 因为Tomainia的孩子们在向他致敬
seems pleased as he is greeted by Tomainian children.
他在一个怀抱着孩子的母亲面前停了下来
He pauses before a woman with a child.
摄影师!
Camera!
甚至连这个婴儿都很兴奋
Even the baby is thrilled
看上去笑得很开心
and seems all smiles at the attention.
阁下他离开了会场
His Excellency leaves the scene
他将沿希克勒大道返回
and will return along Hynkelstrasse,
沿途他将经过Tomainia的现代雕塑杰作:
where he'll pass Tomainia's modern masterpieces:
今日的维纳斯以及未来的思想者
The Venus of Today and the Thinker of Tomorrow.
- 怎么样? - 演讲吗?
- How was it? - The speech?
非常好
Very good.
您在关于犹太人的那段时 语言和动作该更暴力些
Your reference to the Jews might have been more violent.
什么?
What?
这样可以激起人们的愤怒
To arouse the people's anger.
针对犹太人的暴力行为会转移人们对自己目前糟糕境况的注意力
Violence against the Jews might make the people forget their stomach.
你说的没错 最近犹太人区有点太安静了
You're right. Things have been quiet in the ghetto lately.
早上好 Jaeckel先生
Good morning, Mr Jaeckel.
有什么好消息吗?
What's good about it?
还不太糟
Conditions could be worse.
如果您这么认为 那可真是有想象力
If you think so, you have a great imagination.
您听过希克勒的演说了?
You heard Hynkel's speech.
我什么都没听见 我有自己的事要干
I heard nothing. I've got my own troubles.
您比很多人都要好多了
You're better off than a lot of people.
理发师怎么样了?
What about the barber?
还待在医院里
Still in hospital.
战争结束后他就一直待在那里
He's been there since the war.
为什么你不替他把理发店给租出去?
Why not rent his barbershop for him?
他不会让我那样做的 每隔几个星期他就写信来说他快回来了
He won't let me. Every few weeks he writes to say he's coming back.
这么些年都空置着真是可惜
A pity it should be idle all these years.
还担忧什么呢?
Why worry?
政府很快就要把它从他手里没收了
The government will soon take it from him.
也许事情就像你说的那样 这真是一个糟糕的早上
Perhaps you're right. Not such a good morning after all.
你才明白
Now you said it.
Hannah
Hannah.
我的烟袋在壁炉台上面 替我拿一下好吗?
On the mantelpiece is my tobacco pouch. Will you get it?
每个人生活都不如意
Everyone is full of troubles.
是的 每个人 你看看Hannah 多可怜的姑娘啊
Yeah, everyone. Look at Hannah, poor girl.
一个勤恳的劳动者 却找不到工作
A hard worker, can't get a job.
她爸爸死于战争 母亲去年也去世了
Father was killed in the war, mother died last year.
现在她连付房租的钱都没了
Can't earn enough to pay her rent.
我能怎么办?我不能把她赶到街上去
What can I do? I can't throw her out.
您需要再买些烟丝吧
You need some more.
- 你上哪儿去? - 去Shoemaker's夫人的洗衣店
- Where are you going? - Mrs Shoemaker's laundry.
你最好拿着钥匙 我和我太太要出去
You'd better take the key. Mrs Jaeckel and I are going out.
我会把门锁好的
I'm locking up
免得风暴冲锋队又要胡闹
in case the storm troopers start their monkey business again.
雅力安!我们是雅力安人!
Aryan! We're Aryans!
让我们向前进!
And we go marching by!
看那 伙计们!西红柿还有土豆
Look, fellows! Tomatoes and potatoes.
我要拿一箱回家
I'll take a box home.
嘿 开卡车的
Hey, the lorry.
给我停下 明白吗?
Hold it there, will you?
你没权利拿走它们
You have no right!
就记我帐上吧!
Just charge it to my account!
这西红柿真是不错
Nice ripe tomatoes.
你们为什么不做点正事呢?
Why don't some of you do something?
如果我是个男人我就要让你们看看什么叫做男人
If I were a man I'd show you.
你想干什么 宝贝?
What would you do, pretty?
你们里边没人有种敢站出来打一架!
Not one of you has the guts to stand up alone and fight!
这辆卡车就是为了有人反抗时好逃跑用的吧?
Is the lorry in case someone hits back?
闭嘴!
Shut up!
来抓我呀 你会为此获得勋章的
Come and take me. You'll get medals for it.
你们也就是欺负女人以及抢劫无力反抗的人们
You pick on women and rob defenceless people.
伙计们 我们别抢这个可怜的丫头了 把西红柿还给她
Don't rob the poor girl, boys. Give her back her tomatoes.
我又得重新洗了
I'll have to do it again.
你们这群猪!
Pigs!
- 让33号病人进来! - 好的 先生
- Patient 33! - Yes, sir.
一个有意思的病例: 失忆症
An interesting case: Amnesia.
一个犹太裔士兵 打战争结束起就在这儿了
Jewish soldier. Been here since the war.
他总以为只不过在这里待了几个星期
He thinks it's only been weeks.
他知道都发生了些什么吗?
Does he knows what's happened?
不 他唯一感兴趣的看来就是他自己的理发店
No. His one interest seems to be in his barbershop,
他以为自己只不过离开那里几周而已
which he believes he left a few weeks ago.
那么当他看到外面的时候他会很惊讶的
He'll have many surprises.
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
- 什么事? - 33号病人已经离开了
- Yes? - Number 33 is gone.
离开了?他还没检查过啊
Gone? He was to be examined.
不过他已经不见了
But he's disappeared.
不见了?
Disappeared?
别管他了 他也不是多有价值的病例
Let him go. It isn't a serious case.
我们也治不好他
There's little we can do for him.
走开 走开!
Come on, get out of here!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我不知道
I don't know.
离那个远点儿
Leave that alone.
- 别犯傻 - 我没有犯傻!
- Don't be silly. - I'm not silly!
我很感激
I appreciate that.
当你跟我说话时 要先说"嗨希克勒"
When you talk to me, "Hail Hynkel"!
你是谁?
Who are you?
我会让你知道我是谁 跟我到总部去!
I'll show you who I am! Come down to headquarters!
那是我的店
That's my shop.
我才不在乎它是还是不是
I don't care if it is or not.
你想打架是不是? 跟我去总部
Going to put up a fight, are you? Come to headquarters.
我来告诉你
Let me tell you something.
警察吗?那个人袭击我 逮捕他
Policeman?Arrest that man for assault.
- 你 过来! - 放开我
- Come here, you! - Leave me alone.
竟敢袭击风暴冲锋队!
Attacking a storm trooper!
等着同我的律师法庭上见吧
You'll hear from my lawyer.
他咬了我的手指!
He bit my finger!
对不起 我并没想要打到你
Sorry, I didn't mean to hit you.
谢谢你的帮助
I enjoyed that
但你最好还是揍他们一顿
But you'd better beat it.
- 我要叫警察来! - 不行!
- I'll call a policeman. - No!
- 为什么不行? - 你疯了吗?
- Why not? - Are you crazy?
更多的来了!
More are coming!
- 更多的什么? - 等会儿再说!
- More what? - Wait!
快进来
Come in here.
你出什么问题了?不要做蠢事
What's wrong with you? Don't be foolhardy.
这是怎么回事?谁袭击了你们?
What's this? Who hit you?
我想是强盗
I think it was a gang.
你最好去休息一下 我们待会儿会调查的
You'd better get fixed up. We'll investigate later.
现在几点了?
What time is it?
没事了 他们已经走了
All right, they've gone.
谢谢 先生 我好些了
Thanks, mister. That did me a lot of good.
你一定有些紧张
You've sure got some nerve.
我们都应该反抗
We should all fight back.
我们不能独自反抗 但我们可以团结起来打倒他们
We can't fight alone, but we can lick 'em together.
我们干得还不赖 对吧?再见
We didn't do so bad.See you.
你就是那个住医院的理发师!
You're the barber, who was in hospital!
Jaeckel先生提起过你
Mr Jaeckel has talked about you.
我们没想到你回来了
We didn't think you'd come back.
风暴冲锋队会追捕你的
The storm troopers will be after you.
你最好藏起来 我去拿地下室的钥匙
You'd better hide. I'll get the key to the cellar.
- 是这个人吗? - 就是他
- Is this the man? - That's him.
嗨希克勒!
Hail Hynkel!
他是谁?
Who's he?
不要耍我 嗨希克勒!
Don't fool with me. Hail Hynkel!
把手伸出来
Your hands.
等会儿 不是在这里 把他带出去
Just a moment. Not here. Bring him outside
你先把这个干完 拿去
First you'll finish this. Here.
继续 写上去!
Go on, paint that!
等一下 伙计 我有个好主意
Wait a minute, boys. I've got a bright idea.
Schultz长官!
Commander Schultz!
队长
First in command.
副队长
Second in command.
噢 别介意 嘿 你!
Oh, never mind. You!
谁让你们把人吊在灯柱上的?
Who told you to hang people from lampposts?
出了什么事?
What was the trouble?
一个犹太人袭击了风暴冲锋队
A Jew attacking storm troopers.
- 他在什么地方? - 那儿
- Where is he? - There.
放开他
Break ranks.
原来你在这里 把他扶起来
So there you are. Stand him up.
站起来
Get up.
- 是你? - 你还记得我吗?
- You? - Don't you remember me?
- 你救了我的命 -我?
- You saved my life. - Me?
奇怪 我一直以为你是雅力安人
Strange. And I always thought of you as an Aryan.
我是个素食主义者
I'm a vegetarian.
你不记得了吗?我们一起乘飞机逃走
Don't you remember? We got away in my plane.
飞机?
Plane?
之后我们坠机了
Then we crashed.
噢 是的 我想起来了
Now I remember.
啊 你还好吗?
Well, how are you?
我的朋友干了什么?
What's my friend done?
他阻止我的人在他的窗上刷标记
He resisted my men painting his windows.
任何一个勇敢的人都会反抗
Any brave man would resist.
我对此很抱歉
I'm sorry for this.
没关系
No harm.
今后你就不会再有麻烦了
In future you will not be molested again.
如果你和你的朋友需要任何帮助...
If you or your friends ever need help...
谁干的?
Who did that?
我的一个朋友
One of my friends.
希克勒的宫殿是
Hynkel's palace was the centre
世界上最大战争机器的中心
of the world's greatest war machine.
在它后面是充满活力的阿道诺·希克勒
Behind it was the dynamic Adenoid Hynkel,
用他的天才智慧统治着国家
whose genius ran the nation,
繁忙的工作使他一刻都不得停歇
whose ceaseless activity kept him occupied every moment of the day.
Herring元帅在外面等侯
Marshal Herring is waiting.
够了!
Enough!
我想我们现在有一些东西了
I believe we've got something now.
一件防弹衣 材质像丝一样轻
A bulletproof uniform. The material is as light as silk.
在哪里?
Where?
我安排了一个演示 只要两分钟就好
I've arranged for a demonstration. It will only take two minutes.
演示给我看
I can spare one.
Kibitzen博士
Professor Herr Kibitzen.
事实胜于雄辩 这是件防弹衣
Actions speak louder than words. A bulletproof uniform.
百分之百的完美
One hundred percent perfect.
开枪!
Shoot!
远非完美
Far from perfect.
- 我的秘书呢? - 在外面的办公室里
- Where's my secretary? - In the outer office.
叫她过来
Call her.
打封信
Take a letter.
Herring在外面等候 我们有了样非常奇妙的东西
Herring here in the tower room. We've got something marvellous.
我很感兴趣
I shall be up.
这次是降落伞 世界上最袖珍的降落伞
A parachute. The most compact in the world.
穿戴起来就象戴了顶帽子
Worn like a hat.
它能在25英尺的高度开伞
It will open in 25 feet.
演示一下 教授
Demonstrate, professor.
Herring 你为什么要这样浪费我的时间?
Herring, why do you waste my time like this?
把Garbitsch叫来
Send Garbitsch here.
Garbitsch先生正在外等候
Herr Garbitsch is waiting.
够了!
Enough!
这是什么意思?
What's the meaning of this?
花2千5百万去建造集中营?我们需要把钱花在军火生产上
25 million for prison camps? We need to manufacture munitions.
- 我们已经逮捕了一些人 - 有多少?
- We've made a few arrests. - How many?
五千人到一万人...
Five or ten thousand...
每天
a day.
- 每天? - 只是一些抗议者
- A day? - Just a few dissenters.
他们抗议什么?
Dissenting about?
诸如工作时间太长 克扣工资
Working hours, wage cuts,
人工合成的食物 以及面包里木屑的分量
the synthetic food, the quality of the sawdust in the bread.
他们还想要什么?那可都是最好的木料!
What more do they want? It's from the finest lumber!
不过 人民的工作确实有些沉重了 他们需要轮班休息
Nevertheless, the people are overworked. They need diversion.
人民 呸!
The people, bah!
我们也许该给那些犹太人更多颜色看看 把他们的房子烧掉一些
We might go further with the Jews. Burn some of their houses.
袭击犹太人区
An assault on the ghetto.
比这更刺激的 我们多久才能做好入侵Osterlich的准备?
Something more dramatic. When can we be ready to invade Osterlich?
三个月
Three months.
我等不及了 Napaloni的军队可能会抢先入侵
I can't wait. Napaloni's army might invade first.
我们必须现在就发动入侵
We must strike now.
我们还需要国外资本
We'll require foreign capital.
去借!
Borrow it!
银行家们已经拒绝了
The bankers have refused.
有一个人也许会同意给我们贷款：Epstein
One man might make us a loan: Epstein.
- Epstein?他是个犹太人 不是吗? - 是的
- Epstein? He's a Jew, isn't he? - Yes.
好吧 贷款就靠他了 就从Epstein那里贷款
Well, let's be big about it. We'll borrow from Epstein.
考虑到我们对犹太人的政策 这件事办起来可能很困难
It might be difficult in view of our policy towards his people.
那么我们就把政策改一下
Then we'll change our policy.
告诉Schultz 所有迫害犹太人的行为必须马上停止
Tell Schultz all persecution of the Jews must cease.
至少在我们谈成这笔贷款之前
At least till we've negotiated this loan.
我不明白 整个犹太人区为什么这样安静
I don't understand it. The whole ghetto is so quiet.
你很难想象都发生了些什么
You can't imagine what was going on.
这都是希克勒干的好事
This Hynkel business.
你那时没在这里 还依旧躺在医院里不省人事呢
You weren't here, you were in the hospital, unconscious.
你不知道你在医院里过的是多么好的日子啊
You don't appreciate what a good time you were having.
如果情况变得更糟的话 我们可以去Osterlich
If things get worse we can go to Osterlich.
那里仍然是一片自由的乐土
That's still free.
迟早我们得去那里的
Sooner or later we'll have to go.
不管怎样 看到你回来真是太好了
Anyway, it's nice to see you back.
一切好像又回到了从前 是不是?
It's like the old days again, eh?
生意怎样啊?
How's business?
不太好
Very slow.
男人们都在集中营里
The men are in concentration camp.
你该改为女人做头了
You should fix up the women.
改做美发店
The beauty parlour business.
知道该怎么做吗?
Know anything about it?
你可以学学 你可以先拿Hannah练习一下
You can learn. You can practise on Hannah.
Hannah 坐到椅子上去 让我们把你弄漂亮些
Hannah, get in that chair, we'll make you look beautiful.
干嘛?
What for?
他要拿你做练习
He's going to practise on you.
不会弄花我的脸吧?
Not with mud on my face?
不 我们要把你脸上的泥洗掉
No, we'll take some off.
让我变得漂亮吗?
Make me look beautiful?
当然 他不可能把你弄得比现在更糟了
Sure. He can't make you look any worse!
Shoemaker夫人的洗衣店!
Mrs Shoemaker's laundry!
我会把衣服拿给她 你坐在这里好好享受吧
I'll give it to her. You sit here and enjoy yourself.
我明白 我已经看见你们两个眉来眼去的了
I know. I've seen you making eyes.
别听他胡说
Don't pay any attention to him.
你的店整理过了 我很喜欢
I like your shop since it's fixed up.
我希望自己也有一个像这样的生意 光做家务不会有出息的
I wish I had a business like this. There's no future in housework.
如果我能存下些钱的话 也许有一天我也能有个理发店
Maybe if I save my money I can have a barbershop some day.
但我从没存下过钱 钱总是在我指间留不了多久
But I can never save. Money slips through my fingers.
我所挣来的每个便士总是花得一个不剩
I've always lived up to every penny I've earned.
我为什么不开个自己的店呢?你今天来了而明天就要离开
Why shouldn't I? You're here today and gone tomorrow.
你相信上帝吗?
Do you believe in God?
我信 但如果不存在上帝的话 你的生活会有不同吗?
I do. But if there wasn't one, would you live any different?
不会的
I wouldn't.
如果没有人迫害的话 生活本应该是很美好的
Life could be wonderful if people'd leave you alone.
现在情况看起来好点了
Things are looking brighter now.
也许是因为你救过Schultz
Maybe because of you saving Schultz.
他们不来骚扰我们感觉还有些不适应了 真有意思
Funny how they've left us alone.
真太好了 简直让人不敢相信
Too good to be true.
你有做过白日梦吗?我做过的
Do you ever daydream? I do.
只有在做梦的时候我才真正感到快乐
That's the only time I'm really happy: Dreaming.
有时候我神游得太厉害以至于自己都不知道在干什么
Sometimes I get so carried away I don't know what I'm doing.
你也像是那样吧
Aren't you like that?
我们真的很象
We're very much alike.
- 都是经常走神的人 - 你也这样想?
- Both absent-minded. - You think so?
我喜欢经常走神的人
I like absent-minded people.
我喜欢那种把手表投进开水中而鸡蛋却拿在手里的人!
Like the man who put his watch in boiling water and held the egg!
所有的伟人都经常走神 这表示你是个聪明人
All great men are absent-minded. It's a sign you're smart.
我的民族不这样认为
My folks didn't think so.
你还好说 你是因为在战争中受伤了
You have an excuse. You were injured in the war.
而我天生就那样
I was born that way.
真奇怪 女人为什么就不长胡须呢
I wonder why women never grow whiskers.
我这样问是不是很蠢?
Isn't that foolish of me?
我会走路的时候踢到自己 我会...
I could kick myself in the shins, I could...
我给你洗个头吧
I'll give you a shampoo.
我看上去是不是很可爱?
Ain't I cute?
你是怎么弄的?
How did you do it?
你应该给自己做做看
You should try it on yourself.
再打扮一下 你看起来会很帅的
Fixed up, you'd look handsome.
新鲜的马铃薯 4配克（容量单位）一磅!
Four pecks a pound, new potatoes!
卖马铃薯的来了!我必须得走了
The potato man! I have to go.
放松一下
Take it easy there.
你伤到了吗?
Did you hurt yourself?
- 下次小心点 - 这里还有一个
- Careful next time. - Here's another one.
你好吗?
How do you do?
真是奇怪 风暴冲锋队竟然帮助我
Something's happened. The storm troopers helped me up.
如果他们不再厌恶我们 那该多好
How wonderful if they stopped hating us,
如果他们让我们继续像从前那样做自己的生意
if they let us go about our business like we used to.
我们就不用去别的国家 那多好啊
How wonderful if we didn't have to go to another country.
我不想离开这个国家
I don't want to go.
尽管有迫害 但我仍然爱这个地方
With all the persecution, I still love it here.
也许我们不用离开了
Perhaps we don't have to go.
如果他们能让我们继续在这里开心的生活 这不是很好吗?
Wouldn't it be wonderful if they'd let us live and be happy again?
都停下
Full stop.
没什么好用的 甚至连铅笔都不行了
Nothing works! Not even a sharp pencil.
我身边尽是些愚蠢 不合格 不能生育的速记员
I'm surrounded by incompetent, stupid, sterile stenographers.
我给您拿支笔来
I'll get you a pen.
不麻烦了!这封信我不寄了
Don't bother! I won't send it.
滚出去 滚!
Get out, get out!
我们刚发明出了最棒的毒气
We've just discovered the most wonderful poison gas.
它能毒死每一个人...
It will kill everybody...
好的 待会再说
All right. Later.
B76求见Herring先生
B76 to see Herr Herring.
是位女士 我的密探
A lady. My secret agent.
你的密探?让她进来
Your secret agent? Tell her to come here.
让B76进来
Have B76 come right in.
有什么Epstein的新消息吗?
Any news from Epstein?
我们的谍报人员报告说所有的董事会成员都是雅力安人
Our agent reports that all the board of directors are Aryans.
- 贷款极有可能获得通过 - 很好
- The loan's bound to go through. - Good.
军工厂发生了罢工
A strike at the arms factory.
- 带头闹事的人呢? - 抓到五个
- The leader? - Five of them.
- 枪毙他们 - 已经都被枪毙了
- Have them shot. - They were.
有多少人打算参加罢工?
How many were going to strike?
3000人
Three thousand of them.
统统枪毙 我不需要不知足的工人
Have them all shot. I don't want dissatisfied workers.
这些可都是熟练的技术工人
These men are skilled craftsmen.
那就先训练其他工人 然后再把他们枪毙了!
Let's train others first, then shoot them!
我们不能显得仁慈
Cannot afford to be lenient.
可生产的进度会受到影响
The rhythm of production will be affected.
进度...好吧 就让你保住进度吧
Rhythm... All right, have your rhythm.
释放那些罢工者 准许他们回去工作
Spare the strikers and permit them to return to work.
但要给他们做上标记 以备将今后参考
But mark them for future reference.
那是我负责的部门 我会的
That's my department. I'll attend to that. This way.
带头罢工的都是些黑头发的 没一个是金发的
The strike leaders are all brunettes. Not one blond.
麻烦制造者!比犹太人还可恶
Troublemakers! Worse than Jews.
- 那就把他们驱逐出去 - 冷静点
- Then wipe them out! - Doucement.
我们先对付那些犹太人 之后再专心对付那些黑头发的家伙
We'll get rid of the Jews first, then concentrate on the brunettes.
在我们没有一个纯种的雅力安民族之前 我们是不会有和平的
We shall never have peace till we have a pure Aryan race.
多美妙啊!Tomainia 一个金发碧眼的国度
How wonderful! Tomainia, a nation of blue-eyed blonds.
为什么不把欧洲 亚洲 美洲都变成都变成金发碧眼的?
Why not a blond Europe, Asia, America?
- 一个统治全世界所有非雅利安人的 - 独裁者!
- And a brunette dictator. - Of the world!
为什么不呢?
Why not?
"我就是恺撒转世" 整个世界都无力反抗 全都畏惧我
"Aut Caesar aut nullus. " The world's effete, worn out, afraid.
没有国家胆敢与您对抗
No nation would dare oppose you.
世界的独裁者!
Dictator of the World!
这就是您的使命 我们将屠尽犹太人 驱逐非雅利安人
It's your destiny. We'll kill off the Jews, wipe out the brunettes,
然后就会迎来一个纯种的雅力安民族
then will come forth a pure Aryan race.
优秀的金发碧眼的雅力安民族
Beautiful blond Aryans.
他们会爱戴您 如神一般崇拜您
They will love you, they will worship you as a god.
不 你不要那样讲
No, you mustn't say it.
你让我对自己都感到害怕了
You make me afraid of myself.
世界的独裁者!
Dictator of the World!
我们首先入侵Osterlich 之后我们就可以以此恐吓全世界了
We'll invade Osterlich first. After that we can bluff.
其他国家都会乖乖投降的
The nations will capitulate.
整个世界都会在你掌控之中
The world will be under your thumb.
走开!让我单独待一会儿
Leave me! I want to be alone.
我就是恺撒转世
Aut Caesar aut nullus.
统治全世界的帝国!
Emperor of the World!
我的世界
My world.
现在是欢乐时光节目
The happy hour programme.
请按照音乐的节奏工作
Work with the rhythm of music.
我们的下一个曲目：勃拉姆斯匈牙利第五圆舞曲
Our next selection: Brahms' Hungarian Dance number five.
50便士 谢谢
Fifteen cents, please.
欢乐时光节到此结束
Happy hour signing off.
今晚6点 阿道诺·希克勒将会为
At six, Adenoid Hynkel will address
双X徽章的子民们作演说
the children of the double-cross.
看上去一切又跟过去一样了
It seems like the old days again.
这样还能持续多久?
How long is it going to last?
报纸上
In the papers
谣传说希克勒将把犹太人被剥夺的权力归还给他们
it's rumoured that Hynkel's going to give the Jews back their rights.
也许吧
Maybe.
你还想什么?
What do you want?
生意好多了 也再没有人打扰我们了
Business is much better. Nobody interferes with us any more.
这样没让你觉得好些么?
Doesn't that make you feel good?
Jaeckel先生 现在的麻烦是
The trouble, Mr Jaeckel,
如果你已经习惯于之前受到的不公对待 那现在它们没有了你反而会不开心
is you're so used to bad times, you're unhappy without them.
把我的sunday牌鞋子拿来 它们在窗台上
Get my Sunday shoes. They're on the windowsill.
我找不到围巾
I can't find the shawl.
我有一条围巾
I've got a shawl.
出什么事了?
What's going on?
他们正替Hannah化妆好让她上街
They're dressing Hannah up to go out.
是那样吗?
Is that so?
她有一个追求者
She's got a beau.
- 是谁? - 就是那位理发师
- Who is it? - The barber.
现在 转身
Now, turn around.
- 我的天啊!看这双手! - 它们怎么弄成这样子了?
- My dear! Those hands! - What's the matter with them?
那些老茧 它们太硬了
Those calluses. They're so rough.
也许我不该去
Maybe I better not go.
别傻了 他知道那是你做家务弄的
Don't be foolish. He knows you do housework.
等下!我给你找双手套来
Wait! I'll get a pair of mittens.
去看看他是不是准备好了
See if he's ready.
还没呢 他正在给一个秃头男人擦头
Not yet. He's polishing a bald man's head.
坏消息 对Osterlich的入侵将被推迟
Bad news. The invasion of Osterlich
will have to be delayed.
- 什么? - Epstein拒绝借钱给我们
- What? - Epstein refuses to lend the money.
Epstein拒绝了 嗯?
Epstein refuses, eh?
把Schultz给我找来
Send for Schultz.
Epstein拒绝借款给我们
Epstein refuses.
他怎么说?
What did he say?
他反对我们对犹太人施行的迫害
He complained of the persecution
并且说他不会和一个中世纪的疯子做任何交易
and said he wouldn't have any dealings with a mediaeval maniac.
他将要面对一个比他想象中的更疯狂的中世纪疯子!
He'll deal with a mediaeval maniac more than he thinks!
我首先就拿他的那些犹太朋友开刀
First I shall deal with his people.
- 阁下? - 出动风暴冲锋队
- Your Excellency? - Call out the storm troopers.
叫他们在犹太人区来点儿中世纪式的娱乐!
A little mediaeval entertainment in the ghetto!
在当前这样一个非常时期 我认为这个决定是有欠考虑的
At such a time I think it ill-advised.
这样的行为显然会使国家陷入混乱
Such demonstrations demoralise the country.
真的?
Indeed?
你什么时候起开始关心犹太人区了?
Since when do you care about the ghetto?
我是基于党的利益和人道考虑说这话的
I speak in the interests of our party and the cause of humanity.
你需要一个假期
You need a holiday.
呼吸下新鲜的空气
Fresh air.
再来些户外运动
A little outdoor exercise.
我会把你送到集中营去
I'll send you to a concentration camp.
把Schultz抓起来
Place Schultz under arrest.
很好 但记住我的话 你的事业注定要失败
Very well, but remember my words. Your cause is doomed to failure
因为它是建立在对无辜的人们进行愚蠢的迫害上的
because it is built on the stupid persecution of innocent people.
你制定的政策简直比犯罪还糟糕 这是个悲剧性的愚蠢之举
Your policy is worse than a crime. It's a tragic blunder.
背叛者!背叛者!
Traitor! Traitor!
你是个彻头彻尾的的民主主义者
You're a double-dyed democrat!
Schultz 你为什么要背弃我?
Schultz, why have you forsaken me?
阁下 这是您的演说稿
Excellency, here are the notes for your speech.
我不需要
I'll not need them.
我所说的将不针对双X徽章下的子民们了
What I say will not be directed to the children of the double-cross
而是针对犹太人!
but to the children of Israel!
毕竟希克勒还不是那样坏
That Hynkel isn't such a bad fellow after all.
真好笑
Most amusing.
买一个希克勒徽章吧!希克勒徽章!
Get a Hynkel badge! A Hynkel badge!
每个徽章上的图案都很不错的!
A fine photo on each!
- 我们最好赶紧回家 - 没错
- We'd better go home. - Yeah.
快走
Let's hurry.
等等
Wait a minute.
那是什么声音?
What's that?
关掉收音机
Turn off the radio.
是风暴冲锋队!
The storm troopers!
- 关上门! - 把水准备好（灭火用）!
- Bar that door! - Get some water!
让女人和孩子们上楼 把门全部锁上
Get the women and children upstairs. Lock all the doors.
男人们 都留下
You men, stay right here.
我们必须留在这里
We've got to make a stand.
我们与其这样活着不如奋死一搏
We might as well die as live like this.
等等 我们到这家去看看
Wait a minute. We have a social call to make here.
等下!
Wait a minute!
Schultz严令禁止骚扰这个院子里的任何人
Schultz gave strict orders not to molest anyone in this court.
这些犹太人曾袭击过我们
These Jews attacked us.
我可不在意
I don't care.
是命令就得遵守
Orders were to keep out.
你看见了吗!
You saw that!
没办法 这是Schultz的命令
I can't help it. Schultz's orders.
我们走吧
Let's get going.
不管有没有命令 我都要逮到那个丫头
Orders or not, I'm going to get that girl.
出去!
Out!
Schultz被逮捕了!
Schultz arrested!
听到了么?元首逮捕了Schultz
Hear that? He's arrested Commander Schultz.
- 一个犹太人使我们的长官堕落了 - 杀了这些社会的虱子!
- A Jew corrupted our commander. - Let's kill the louse!
Schultz被控叛国 你们都知道是为什么
Schultz is accused of treason, and you know why.
Schultz同那个理发师是朋友
Schultz was a friend of that barber.
我们去抓住那个理发师!我们要抓住那个理发师!
Let's get the barber! We want the barber!
是风暴冲锋队!
It's the storm troopers!
- 到屋顶去 - 不
- Get on the roof. - No.
- 他们会杀了你! - 我会同他们战斗的
- They'll kill you! - I'll fight.
别傻了 你会被杀掉的 到屋顶上去
Don't be a fool, you'll be murdered. Get on the roof.
好了 我们到了 把门撞开!
All right, here we are. Smash in the door!
来吧 让我们给那位理发师"理个发"
Come on, we'll give the barber a haircut!
炸弹在哪里?
Where are the bombs?
他们毁了我的理发店!
There goes the barbershop!
别难过了 我们还可以重头开始
Never mind. We can start again.
我们可以去Osterlich 那里仍然是自由的国度
We can go to Osterlich. That's still free.
Jaeckel先生说那里是个很美的地方
Mr Jaeckel says it's beautiful.
到处是绿色的田野 人们种植苹果和葡萄
Wonderful green fields, and they grow apples and grapes.
他兄弟在那里有一个葡萄园
His brother's got a vineyard.
Jaeckel说他会带我一起去
Mr Jaeckel said he'd take me with him.
现在我们可以一起离开了
Now we can all go together.
我们一起在那个地方生活的话一定很美妙
It'll be wonderful living in the country,
比一个到处冒着浓烟的旧城市好多了
much better than a smoky old city.
而且如果我们努力工作并省吃俭用 我们就能存下一笔钱
And if we work hard and don't eat much, we can save money
然后买下一个养鸡场
and buy a chicken farm.
到时候就能靠养鸡挣钱了
There's money to be made in chickens.
看那颗星星!
Look at that star!
是不是很美!
Isn't it beautiful!
希克勒用尽所有权力也永远得不到它
Hynkel with all his power can never touch that.
好了 已经风平浪静了
All right, the coast is clear.
Schultz逃出来了 他正藏在我的地窖里
Commander Schultz escaped. He's hiding in my cellar.
他将在半夜主持召开一个会议 此外他希望你也到场
He's holding a meeting at midnight and he wants you to be there.
Hannah 你来帮Jaeckel太太一起准备晚餐
Hannah, you come and help Mrs Jaeckel with the supper.
好的 我马上就下来
All right, I'll be down.
我不明白 这顿不可思议的午夜晚餐...
I don't understand it. This crazy midnight supper...
Schultz想从我们这里得到什么?
What does this Schultz want of us?
- 他想让我们去把宫殿炸掉 - 什么?
- He wants us to blow up the palace. - What?
我们犹太人决不能卷入这种可怕的事情中去
We Jewish people shouldn't get mixed up in such a business.
我明白 但是Schultz已经把他们都说服了
I know it but Schultz has them all hypnotised.
- 我知道他正策划着什么不好的事情 - 当然
- I knew he was up to some mischief. - Sure he is.
我发现他在你的某个布丁里放了一枚硬币
I found him putting a coin in one of your puddings.
别担心 我已经处理好了 等着瞧吧
Don't worry, I've fixed everything. Wait and see.
先生们 大家能听我说会儿吗?
Gentlemen, may I claim your indulgence for a moment?
我们今晚聚在一起为的是将这个国家从暴君的统治下拯救出来
We are here tonight to rid the country of a tyrant.
为了实现这个目标 我们中的某个人必须为此献出生命
In order to carry this out one of us must die.
在古代 Langobardians的雅丽安部落
In ancient times the Aryan tribe of the Langobardians
将活人祭献给他们的神Thor
made human sacrifice to the god Thor.
在盛宴上 牺牲者用抽签的方式选定
At a feast by lottery the victim was chosen.
今晚 在这个盛宴上 你们中的一人将被选中
Tonight, at this feast, one of you will be chosen.
每个人都会得到一个布丁
Each man will receive a pudding.
其中一个布丁里面藏了一枚硬币
Concealed in one of these is a coin.
谁拿到它就必须献出自己的生命
Whoever gets it must give up his life
但他将作为光荣的烈士载入历史的长卷
but he will join the long line of history's noble martyrs
他将把自己的祖国从暴君手中拯救出来
and will rid his country of a tyrant.
我知道这是我们所有人的愿望
I know that it is the wish of all of us
今晚被选中的人就要为Tomainia献出生命
to be chosen this night to die for Tomainia.
我很愿意亲自投身这个严峻的考验 但我不能...
Much as I should like to participate in this ordeal, I cannot...
为什么?
Why?
你不明白么? 他太有名了
Don't you understand? He's too well known.
被选中的这个人要像我们一样默默无闻
It must be somebody like us.
我不这么认为
I can't see it like that.
这事关我的荣誉 很令人为难
It is a question of my honour. It is very embarrassing.
Schultz 我替我的朋友向你道歉
Commander Schultz, I apologise for my friend.
请允许我代表自己还有其他人说
Let me say, on behalf of myself and the others,
我们认为 能为国捐躯是一份巨大的荣耀
that we consider it a great privilege to die for our country.
非常好
Very well, then.
先生们 我现在应该退场了 让命运来选择出我们的解放者吧
Gentlemen, I shall now retire until fate has chosen the liberator.
到那时... 嗨 希克勒...
Until then... Hail Hynk...
我在说什么啊?
What am I saying?
先生们 我们已经以自己的名誉发过誓了
Gentlemen, we have pledged our honour.
那么开始吧!
Proceed!
先生们 硬币在这里!
Gentlemen, the coin is here!
炸掉宫殿伤害人命!
Blowing up palaces and wanting to kill people!
我们的麻烦已经够多了!
We're in enough trouble!
Hannah是对的 我们都被愚弄了
Hannah's right. We've all been foolish.
我们该做的就是待在家里 管好我们自己的事情
Our place is at home, looking after our own affairs.
报纸说Schultz可能躲在犹太人区里
The papers say Schultz may be in the ghetto.
拿去 你自己看吧
Here, read it for yourself.
Hannah 读来听听
Hannah, read that.
"前司令官Schultz神秘失踪"
"Mystery surrounds the disappearance of ex-Commander Schultz. "
"警察总部相信他很可能藏身于犹太人区里"
"At police HQ it was believed he may be hiding in the ghetto. "
"一名犹太人理发师 据报告是Schultz的朋友
"A certain Jewish barber, reported to be a friend of Schultz,
正被四处寻找以便问讯"
is wanted for questioning. "
我?
Me?
只是询问而已 还不是很严重
Only for questioning. Not too serious.
Meyerberg也只是带去被询问 但之后我们再没见过他
Meyerberg was only wanted for questioning. We never saw him again.
- 是谁? - 是我 Mann先生
- Who is it? - It's me, Mr Mann.
你有听他们说Schultz藏身在犹太人区的事吗?
Did you hear what they're saying about Schultz hiding in the ghetto?
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
你不觉得如果他们在您的屋子里找到他的话后果是很严重的?
Don't you think it's serious if they find him in the house?
你没有意识到么?
Don't you realise?
现在到处都是密探!
there are spies everywhere!
密探?
Spies?
出什么事了?
What's the matter?
他正被通缉以便问讯
He's wanted for questioning.
他在什么地方?
Where's the Commander?
就在隔壁
In the next room.
如果Schultz在这里被发现
If Commander Schultz is found in this house,
我们都会被送进集中营
we'll all go to a concentration camp
然后全部砍头!
and have our heads cut off, too!
我说的对不对?
Am I arguing?
我们别管他了
Then get rid of him.
你不能把他扔到大街上去
You can't throw him out.
当然不是这样
Of course not.
但我想知道他准备在这里呆多久
But I'd like to know how long he's going to stay here.
你的早餐在桌上
Your breakfast is on the table.
谢谢 我的早餐在家里等着我呢
Thank you. I have breakfast waiting at home.
搜查每个房间
Search every house.
- 现在又是干什么? - 他们正在搜查Schultz
- What now? - They're looking for Schultz.
他就在这里的一个房间里
He's in one of these houses.
他们总是在搜查什么人
They're always looking for somebody.
是我 让我进去
It's me. Let me in.
风暴冲锋队正在搜查每个房间
The storm troopers are searching every house.
告诉他
Tell the Commander.
- 你跟他说了吗? - 是的
- Did you tell him? - Yes
- 是什么人来了? - 风暴冲锋队
- What is it? - The storm troopers.
- 什么? - 你们两个最好都到屋顶上去
- What? - You'd both better get on the roof.
我们不能把所有的东西都留下
We can't leave all these things.
你们都来替我把东西装到箱子里去
All of you, pack my cases.
你装那个
You pack that.
把架子清干净
Clear this shelf.
把这个和这个装进去
Pack this and this.
这个决不能被发现
This mustn't be found.
开门
Open the door.
他们来了!快上屋顶去!
They're here! Get up on the roof.
没有东西留下了!
Nothing left behind!
- 我的高尔夫球棍! - 还有帽盒!
- My golf clubs! - The hatbox!
- 拿上这个 - 快点 我们赶紧逃!
- Take this. - Come on, let's hurry!
- 你这是上哪儿? - 跟他走
- Where are you going? - With him.
迟些时候他就回来
You'll see him later.
- 晚上我来找你 - 好的
- I'll meet you tonight. - All right.
拿上这个
Take this.
快!
Quick!
以希克勒的名义 我命令里边的人开门!
Open in the name of Hynkel!
停下!
Stop!
好好看看你在什么地方!
Look where you are!
我看不见 等一下
I can't see, wait a moment.
我的包!你把它扔了
My bag! You drop it.
它在这儿呢 就在这里
It's right here. Here it is.
别把另一个给丢掉了
Don't drop the other one.
我的高尔夫球棍 不 我的高尔夫球棍!
My golf clubs, not my golf clubs!
过来 他们会发现你的
Come here. They'll see you.
快 走这边!
Quick, this way!
喂 轻点儿!
Woah, steady!
- 当心点 - 遵命 长官
- Now be careful. - Yes, sir.
你没把脖子扭断真够幸运的
Lucky you didn't break your neck.
你会原谅我的
You'll pardon me.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你看好后面 站住!
You guard the back. Wait a minute!
我不得不再次打扰你
I'll have to bother you again.
他在那儿
There he is.
早上好啊 感觉怎么样?
Good morning. How are you?
还行
So-so.
这是你的朋友
Here's your friend.
记住 你有权保持沉默
Remember. Your silence will be appreciated.
把他送上囚车
Take him to the wagon.
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
吸烟室
Smoking room.
噢 得了 走这边!
Come on, this way!
是Osterlich
Osterlich!
我很高兴的宣布我们终于
I am pleased to announce that we are at last
作好向Osterlich进军的准备了
ready to march on Osterlich.
正是天才的陆军元帅Herring 使它成为可能
This was made possible by the genius of Field Marshal Herring,
现在我应该授予他一枚勋章以表示对他的敬意
upon whom I shall now pin a token of my regard.
转个身 噢不!
Turn around. No!
先生们
Gentlemen.
为了陆军元帅Herring!
To Field Marshal Herring!
为了入侵Osterlich的顺利进行!
To the invasion of Osterlich!
你这头大象!
Elephant!
等等
Wait.
Napaloni的军队正在向Osterlich边境集结
Napaloni's army is on the Osterlich front.
已经有60,000人在边界上了
60,000 men are on the border.
随时准备占领Osterlich!
To take Osterlich!
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe it.
你不敢相信!
You can't believe it!
你让他抢在我们的前面了
You let him steal a march on us.
我已经都布置好了
I had the ground covered.
向Napaloni宣战!
Declare war on Napaloni!
动员陆军和空军的每个师
Mobilise every division of the army and air force.
立刻对Bacteria发动攻击!
Attack Bacteria at once!
- 但是... - 照我说的做!
- But... - Do as I tell you!
- 这太疯狂了 - 闭嘴!
- Madness. - Shut up!
那么您签署这个吧?
Will you sign this?
这是什么?
What is it?
宣战书
A declaration of war.
好的 给我一枝钢笔!
Yes. A pen!
我这就签署它
I'll sign it.
拿钢笔来!
A pen!
我这就签署它! Napaloni...
I'll sign it! Napaloni...
- 是Napaloni的电话 - 等等
- It's Napaloni. - Wait a minute.
Napaloni?的电话
Napaloni?
你跟他说
You talk to him.
我该怎么说呢?
What'll I say?
说些好听的 和蔼可亲的 令人高兴的话
Be nice, affable, pleasant.
好吧 好吧 你好吗?
Well, well, how are you?
不 他已经不怎么玩了
No, he hasn't been playing much.
你想同阁下他通话?
His Excellency?
但是他现在嗓子有点哑
Just now he's a little hoarse.
不 我的意思是他现在不能说话
No, I mean he can't talk.
也许我能代为转达?
May I take a message?
他说毫无疑问您已经听说了在Osterlich发生的事情
He says no doubt you've heard about Osterlich.
他想就此事同你商谈一下
He wants to discuss it.
让他过来
Ask him to come here.
元首阁下邀请您前来Tomainia一同讨论这件事情
His Excellency invites you to Tomainia to discuss the matter.
太好了 我会做好准备工作的
Very well. I'll make the arrangements.
他这就赶来了
He's coming.
很好
Good.
我们将向他们展示有史以来这个世界上最为强大的军队
We'll put on the greatest military show the world has ever known.
这样Napaloni就会将入侵Osterlich的资格让给我
Napaloni will leave the invasion of Osterlich to me.
那这个怎么办呢?
And this?
- 这是什么? - 您签署的宣战书
- What is it? - Your declaration of war.
现在我宣布和平了!
Peace is declared!
2,975,000名市民热切的聚集在火车站广场
2,975,000 eager citizens are massed in the station square
等候Benzino Napaloni的到来
awaiting Benzino Napaloni.
进入车站的是我们元首 他正准备会见他的客人
Entering the station is our Phooey, ready to greet his guest.
这次会面将会巩固
This will cement the friendship
我们的元首与Bacteria的独裁者之间的友谊
between our Phooey and the Dictator of Bacteria.
元首阁下正要向Bacterian大使致意
His Excellency is about to greet the Bacterian ambassador.
你好吗?
How do you do?
看好那些摄影师
See about the photography.
告诉新闻媒体要保证把我们的元首照得好一点
Tell the press to see that our Phooey is well photographed.
- 而不是他后脑勺! - 明白 长官
- Not the back of his head! - Yes, sir.
Napaloni乘坐的火车就要进站了
Napaloni's train is coming into the station.
Napaloni 和他的妻子将从
From a pink and white carriage
一节粉红色和白色装饰的车厢走出来
Napaloni and his wife will step out
而阿道诺·希克勒将致欢迎词
and Adenoid Hynkel will deliver his address of welcome.
现场出现的混乱是怎么回事?
What's all this mix-up-a?
他们错过站台了
They've gone too far.
别慌!
At ease!
把地毯拿来
Bring the carpet.
我们为什么不下车呢?
Why can't-a we get out here?
没有铺地毯
No-a carpet.
谁在乎呢?
Who cares?
我 Napaloni 没有地毯我决不下车
Me, Napaloni, I never get out without a carpet.
铺这里 快
Lay it down here. Quick.
- 火车倒回去了 - 什么?
- It's going back. - What?
等火车停下我们就出去
Let's get out while it's stopping.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
把它拿走!
Take it away!
在他们想好该停哪儿之前我们就待在这儿
Stay here until they've made up their minds.
现在有地毯了 把它铺好!
You got-a da carpet. Put it down!
他来了
Here he is.
- 我的朋友! - Napaloni!
- My friend! - Napaloni!
这真令人愉快 欢迎来到Tomainia 这边走
This is indeed a pleasure. Welcome to Tomainia. This way.
拍照!
Pictures!
当然 敬礼!
Sure. Salute!
再照一张
Another, please.
我很荣幸 希克勒 我的朋友
This is a pleasure, my friend Hynkel.
再来一张好吗?
You want another?
来吧
There.
我的大使在什么地方?你好 Spook
Where's-a my ambassador? Hello, Spook.
你感觉怎么样?请帮忙照顾一下我妈妈
How do you feel? Look after mamma.
希克勒 你之前有见过我的妻子吗?
Hynky, did you meet-a my wife?
就是她 我们走吧
That's her. Let's go.
Tomainia... 非常漂亮 非常漂亮
Tomainia... very nice, very nice.
您的钟慢了一点儿
Your clock is-a slow.
请这边走
This way.
非常友好的人民
It's-a very nice people.
人们都很善良
The people are very nice.
谢谢你
Thank you.
他是我丈夫!
He's my husband!
你们弄错了!你犯了个大错误!
You make a mistake! You make a big-a mistake!
Napaloni的军队不应入侵Osterlich 它是我的!
Napaloni's army shall not invade Osterlich. It belongs to me!
我们不该提Osterlich的事情
We shall not discuss the Osterlich situation.
这次会面要让他对您的个人魅力留下深刻印象
This interview is to impress on him the force of your personality.
让他感到你比他优等
To make him feel your superiority.
Napaloni是个咄咄逼人 盛气凌人的家伙
Napaloni is aggressive, domineering.
我们一定要让他一举一动都乖乖的按照我们的安排来
We must put him in his place.
但是怎样才能办到?
But how?
运用用心理暗示
By means of psychology.
使他感觉到自己低人一头
By making him feel inferior.
这可以巧妙的办到
This can be done subtly.
比方说
For instance,
我会做些安排使得他只能仰望您
I have arranged that he'll be looking up at you,
而您则是俯看他
you looking down at him.
他的位置将会是次要的
His position will be inferior.
之后我们会迫使他坐在您的半身像旁
Then again we shall seat him here beside your bust
这样如果您表现出很轻松的样子 会对他是非常大的刺激
so that if you relax that will always be glaring at him.
他现在在什么地方?
Where is he now?
他正在休息
Resting.
我已经安排好了 他将会从最远的门进入这个房间
I have arranged that he will enter from the far end of the room.
这将又是一次心理学运用的胜利
Another psychological triumph.
从房间的那端一直走过来 他将会非常尴尬
He will have the embarrassment of walking the entire floor.
Napaloni先生正离开他的房间
Signor Napaloni is now leaving his room.
他就要来了 快 给我一朵花
He's coming. Quick, give me a flower.
总之 在他面前 你总要高他一等
At all times be above him, before him.
进出房间 你一定要是第一个
Entering or leaving you must be first.
你好 希克勒!
Hello, Hynky!
你感觉好吗?
How are you feel?
我的独裁兄弟!
My brother dictate!
你是一个非常好的小个子 很高兴再次见到你
You're a nice-a little man. I'm so glad to see you again.
还有Garbitsch 我的朋友!
And my friend the Garbitsch!
这真是个讨人喜欢的地方
This is a lovely place.
我感觉很舒适
I feel-a fine.
我刚冲个凉水澡 如果你把水管好好修一下的话
I just had a nice cold shower. When you have the plumbing fixed
它就不会老是出毛病了
it'll be in good shape.
你能坐下说话吗?
Won't you sit down?
好吧 希克勒 我的独裁者朋友 你
Well, Hynky, my dictator friend, you.
能不能高一点!
I must be a-growing!
你们给了我什么?一把婴儿椅子?
What do they give me? A baby stool?
这不是给我用的 我喜欢高一点的地方
This is not for me. I like it better upstairs.
Garbitsch 这真是一个可爱的国家 人民也非常友好
Garbitsch, this is a lovely country. Very nice-a people.
我知道公众们的热情
I thought the public enthusiastic.
当然 他们喜欢看见新的面孔
Sure. They like to see new faces.
我为发生在Napaloni夫人身上的不幸表示抱歉
I'm sorry for the mishap that occurred to Madam Napaloni.
怎么回事?
What's that?
我为发生在Napaloni夫人身上的...的...
I'm sorry for the Napaloni that occurred at the... at...
Napaloni夫人在车站时的那件事
Madam Napaloni at the station.
她不习惯被公众关注的生活 她适应不了
She's not used to public life. She can't take it.
火柴
Match.
我很抱歉...
I'm sorry...
不用道歉 我找到一根了
Don't apologise. I find-a one.
我只是对这个宫殿感到着迷
I'm simply crazy about this palace.
象牙还有黄金 讨人喜欢的组合
Ivory and gold. A lovely combination.
别做那些不切实际的幻想了
Gets away from that gingerbread idea.
告诉我 Garbitsch 接下来是什么节目?
Tell me something, Garbitsch, what's on the programme?
今天傍晚有盛大晚宴
The grand ball this evening.
以及一场阅兵式
And a review of the army.
那不会花很长时间的!
That won't take-a long!
我恐怕它会的
I'm afraid it will.
那么说你有一支庞大的军队了 哼?
So you got a big army, huh?
这我不用谦逊
Modesty forbids.
好像我听说过它
Seems I've heard about it.
我想我得刮一下胡子
I think I'll get me a shave.
我们有理发店
We have a barbershop.
是吗?
Is that so?
你面颊看上去也有些发青了 我们一起去怎样?
You look blue under the gills. What do you say we go together?
- 很乐意 - 很好!
- Delighted. - Good!
非常好 这边走
Very well, this way.
到了 我闻到了味道
This is it. I can-a smell 'em.
非常香
This is-a very sweet.
这里曾是图书馆
It was the library.
一家不错的理发店
A good barbershop.
- 太老式了 - 是吗?
- Too old-fashioned. - Is that so?
当我刮胡子的时候 我喜欢有什么东西可以看
When I get shaved I like something to look at.
因此我在这里安装了玻璃墙
So I'm putting in glass walls.
这样 我可以欣赏对面的那些山
This way, I shall have a view of the mountains.
这里也是,可以透过玻璃天花板看出去
And this, a view through the glass ceiling.
- 楼上是什么? - 宴会厅
- What's above? - The ballroom.
在我的避暑行宫里也有个理发店
In my summer palace I have a barbershop.
是吗?
Is that so?
也用玻璃墙壁
Also with glass walls.
你没告诉过我!
You don't tell me!
里边还有金鱼
With goldfish inside.
金鱼在墙壁里游泳?那你如何喂它们?
Goldfish swimming inside the walls? How do you feed them?
当然不能 他们全都死了 这就是为什我正在修建另一座
You can't, they're all dead. That's why I'm building a new one.
- 非常有趣的! - 你喜欢吗?
- Very interesting! - You like it?
这里是希克勒体育馆 在50万观众面前
The Hynkel stadium. Before half a million spectators
史上最盛大的阅兵仪式正在举行
the greatest ever display of arms marches by in review.
我们敬爱的元首和他的独裁者朋友已经就座
Our beloved Phooey and I'll-Dig-a-Ditchy are seated,
一同亲历这个历史性的事件
thrilled by this historic event.
什么?
What?
没什么 我不过在吃东西
Nothing. I'm just chewing.
来点花生?
Some peanuts?
- 我有的 - 看上去不错
- I've had some. - Good shape.
拿去 Spook
Here you are, Spook.
现在通过的是 Tomainia的重型火炮部队
Now passing, Tomainia's heavy artillery.
还行
It's all right.
我想让你看看我的新式轰炸机 他们就快来了
I want to show you my new bombing planes. They're coming over.
- 从哪儿来的? - Aroma
- Where from? - Aroma.
Aroma?那有400英里远
Aroma? That's 400 miles away.
没错 我不知道为什么他们现在都还没有来
Right. I don't know what's detaining them.
现在通过的是 Tomainia的轻型火炮部队
Now passing, Tomainia's light artillery.
真的非常轻!
Very light!
现在出现的是装甲坦克部队 Tomainia军队的骄傲
And here come the armoured tanks, the pride of Tomainia's army.
最新式的设计
The latest design, the last word
现代战争的终极武器
in modern warfare.
我怎么没看到螺旋桨?就是潜水的时候用的!
Where's the propellers? For going under the water!
潜水?
Under water?
你从没听说过坦克是能潜水还有飞上天的吗?
You never heard of tanks that go under the water and fly up-a stairs?
- 那是什么? - 能潜水能飞上天的
- What's that? - Under the water and in the air.
这早淘汰了!我们现在正集中精力研制能飞行的无畏战舰
Obsolete now! We're concentrating on flying dreadnoughts.
- 那是什么? - 我的飞机!
- What's that? - My planes!
现在飞过的是 希克勒的第34飞行大队
Now passing, Hynkel's flying division number 34.
是我们的飞机!
Our planes!
你说得没错 他们是你的飞机
You're right. They're yours.
Garbitsch!入侵Osterlich的事情办的怎么样了?
Garbitsch! The invasion of Osterlich.
我们的部队 坦克和枪械会沿着边界伪装好
Our troops, tanks and guns will be hidden along the border.
为消除疑虑 您得去打猎
To disarm suspicion, you will go hunting.
之后您得去趟Pretzelburg
Then you will show up at Pretzelburg,
在那里检阅军队 乘车进入Osterlich
meet the army, step into a car and cross over into Osterlich.
Herring和我将会在首都等候您
Herring and I will be waiting at the capital.
但首先得让Napaloni撤走他的军队
First Napaloni must remove his troops.
这事今晚就得确定
To be decided tonight.
Napaloni在什么地方?
Where is Napaloni?
我这就去找他
I'll look for him.
我建议您邀Napaloni夫人跳个舞
It might be advisable for you to dance with Madam Napaloni.
这很重要
It'll carry weight.
你说我要（跟那个胖女人）!
You mean I will!
你去找到他!找到后立刻向我报告
You find him! And let me know at once.
- Napaloni夫人... - 元首阁下!
- Madam Napaloni... - Your Excellency!
为何您如此忧郁?
Why so triste?
因为没人理我
Because I no speak.
没人?那我能荣幸的邀请您
No? May I have the pleasure?
共舞一曲吗?
Allow me.
夫人 您的舞技可是非同一般的
Madam, your dancing was superb.
高超
Excellent.
非常好
Very good.
Good.
- 我亲爱的阿道诺 - Benzino!
- My dear Adenoid. - Benzino!
我正在找你
I've been looking for you.
让我们去静一些的地方
Let's go to some quiet place
好好把事情谈谈
where we can talk-a things over.
- 就照你说的办 - 非常好 去餐厅!
- As you wish. - An excellent idea. To the buffet!
当然 这边走
Of course, this way.
在Tomainian 有这样一句谚语...
There's a Tomainian proverb...
真好笑 我希望我听明白了
Funny. I wish I understand it.
现在我们谈谈边境的问题吧
Now about the border.
好的 没有问题
Yes. No problem.
这事儿应该不麻烦
It should be no trouble.
- 出什么事了? - 等等
- What's the matter? - Wait.
你 也都出去!
You, too. Out!
出去
Out.
- 那么...边境问题 - 是的
- So... the border question. - Yes.
具体的来说 正式的说
It's just a matter of detail. Formalities.
草莓!
Strawberries!
- 你有英国芥末吗? - 英国芥末
- Have you any English mustard? - English mustard.
- 那玩意儿不是非常辣吗? - 非常辣
- That's da hot-a stuff? - Very hot.
看起来不错
Good shape.
乳酪
Cream.
希克勒 我打算把这件事情简单化
Hynky, I'm going to make this very simple.
你同意不入侵Osterlich
You agree not to invade Osterlich,
我同意不入侵Osterlich
I agree not to invade Osterlich.
我们签署协议 之后我就把我的军队从边境撤下来
We sign, then I remove my troops from the border.
等你的军队撤离后 我就签字
When your troops are gone, I sign.
好的
That's-a right.
等等 你没听明白
Just a minute, you don't understand.
首先我们签署协议 之后我撤走军队
First we sign, then I remove-a da troops.
- 准确的说 我要后签协议 - 等等
- Precisely. I sign after. - Just a minute.
嗨 Spook 协议拿来
Hey, Spook, treaty.
拿着这个
Hold-a dis.
现在 你看 你先签署这个协议
Now, look, you sign-a dis treaty first.
之后我撤走我的军队
Then I remove my troops after.
我们还争什么呢?
Why are we arguing?
你说要我先撤军
You said I remove first.
当你的军队还在的时候 我不会签字
I can't sign while they're there.
- 在你签字之前我不会撤军 - 为什么不?
- I won't remove them till you sign.- Why not?
- 我为什么要这样做? - Osterlich是一个自由的国家!
- Why should I? - Osterlich is a free country!
你的军队就那里
Your soldiers are there.
你不签字他们会一直待在那里
And they'll stay until you sign.
我会把他们赶走
I'll blow them off.
我们没办法达成一致
This won't get us anywhere.
用一句古老的拉丁谚语来说...
To quote an old Latin phrase...
草莓!
Strawberries!
我的三明治在哪?再来一个!
Where's-a my sandwich? Another one!
我不会签署者个协议!
I don't get this treatment in my own joint!
我们就不能耐心的讨论这件事吗?
Can't we discuss this without passion?
我不是没有耐性 我只不过...
I'm not-a passionate. I'm just...
我想要他签署协议
I want him to sign the treaty.
要是签署这样一个协议 我的人民会怎么想
What would my people think, signing such a treaty
而你的军队还依旧在边境上?
when your soldiers are on the border?
你不签字我就不撤军!
I won't move until you sign!
除非你把边境上的军队全部撤离否则我不会签字!
Not until you clear the border will I sign!
那他们就原地不动
Then they remain.
那我就撵走他们
Then I kick them off.
你的军队敢再前进一步我的火炮就会把你们轰成碎片!
One move from you and my artillery will blow you to pieces!
那么我的飞机就会把你的火炮炸成那样!
And my aeroplanes will bomb your artillery like that!
你想开始一场世界战争吗?
You want-a start a world war?
我要把你和这个世界扔进海里!
You and the world I'll throw in the ocean!
草莓!
Strawberries!
阁下 我们...
Your Excellency, we have...
我之前在走廊里放了一把枪
I got-a my guns here in the pass
我这就把他轰成碎块
and I'll blow him to pieces.
出什么事了?什么让你如此痛苦?
What's the matter? What ails you?
这不像你
This isn't like you.
嗨 Garbitsch 过来
Hey, Garbitsch, come here.
希克勒他是怎么了?
What's with Hynky?
他的草莓上沾了芥末
Mustard on his strawberries.
你还指望从希克勒哪里得到什么吗?
What else can you expect from Hynky?
我的小宝贝!
My little bambino!
你不能这样对待Bacteria
You cannot treat Bacteria this way.
我要把Bacterian的人民撕得粉碎 就像这样!
I'll take the Bacterian people and tear them apart, like this!
看看他都在做什么!这是对我的人民的侮辱!
Look what he's doing! It's an insult to my people!
他就是个撕开的意大利面条!
He's-a tearing spaghetti!
他要么签署这个协议否则我们就来一场战争!
He sign-a the treaty or we have a war!
给我什么东西!快点 随便给我点什么东西!
Give me a-something! Quick, give me a-something!
- 我有一个约会 - 怎么回事?
- I have an appointment. - What's this?
媒体 会议进行得怎样了?
Press. How's the conference progressing?
非常成功 你是怎么进来的?
Very successfully. How did you get in?
他是怎么进来的?
How did he get here?
你知道对记者的规定
You know the regulations about reporters.
不论任何情况都不得进入这座宫殿 明白吗?
No one is to enter the palace under any circumstances, understand?
能否透露一下细节...
There are minor details to be cleaned up...
抱歉 我们还有事要办
Excuse me, we're busy.
全世界都会知道我们正在对抗!
The whole world will know we're fighting!
- 那又怎么样? - 我们就不能达成某种一致吗?
- So what? - Can't we come to an agreement?
他签署的时候
When he signs.
我什么也不签
I sign nothing.
我得跟你单独谈谈 介意吗?
I must speak to you alone. Do you mind?
介意?我不介意!
Mind? I don't mind!
签字!签字!
Sign! Sign!
他会从中获利的
He'll have the advantage.
这只不过是张小纸片而已
It's a mere scrap of paper.
等他的军队从边境撤离的时候 我们就能入侵了
When his troops are off the border, we can move in.
我将签署协议
I'll sign.
什么?拿着这个
What? Hold-a this.
啊 我的小个子希克勒!我的独裁者兄弟!
Ah, my little Hynky! My dictator brother!
我就知道我们之间不会有矛盾的
I knew we have-a no trouble.
有两个囚犯穿着军官的制服逃走了
Two prisoners escaped in officers' uniforms.
拉响警报!有两个囚犯逃走了
Sound the alarm! Two prisoners escaped.
这些飞机是来搜寻我们的
The planes are searching for us.
往森林走
The woods.
不 往这边的开阔地走 那才是通向边境的路
No, the open. The border's that way.
入侵Osterlich
The invasion of Osterlich.
要么现在要么永远都不
Now or never.
鸭子
Ducks.
你听见了吗?
Did you hear that?
从那边传来的声音
It came from over there.
你从什么地方弄来的?
A yodeller. Where did you get that outfit?
- 什么? - 不要回答!
- What? - Don't answer back!
Schultz在什么地方?你不肯说 是吗?
Where's Schultz? You won't talk, eh?
- 等我们把他带到营地他就会说了 - 走吧
- He will when we get him to camp. - Come on.
那里就是Pretzelburg村
There it is. The village of Pretzelburg.
如果我们能通过那里我们就安全了
If we can pass through there we're safe.
穿过这片森林?
Through the woods?
那里到处都是士兵 要是被他们发现立刻就会被怀疑的
They're swarming with soldiers. They'd suspect us at once.
不管你看见任何人 都不要东张西望
If you see anyone, don't look right or left.
我们必须唬住他们
We must bluff our way through.
他们来了
Here they come.
能看见他们正在干什么吗?
Can you see what they're doing?
- 看这里 - 继续走!
- Looking this way. - Keep going!
他们正跟着我们 我们该逃跑吗?
They're following us. Shall we run?
当然不
Certainly not.
稍微跑一点点?
Just a little bit?
继续走!
Keep walking!
我们可以走得快一点
We could walk faster.
你决定吧
Make up your mind.
我们走慢点?
Slow down?
- 不! - 不要慌张
- No! - There's no hurry.
他在这里!
He's here!
集合!
Sound assembly!
注意!
Attention!
托枪!
Present arms!
要转身吗?
Turn back?
不 继续走!
No, keep going!
嗨希克勒!
Hail Hynkel!
阁下 一切尽在掌控之中
Your Excellency, everything is under control.
- 很好 - 很好
- Good. - Good.
我已经同在Osterlich的Herring元帅联系过了
I have been in communication with Marshal Herring in Osterlich.
沿线已经做好了保卫工作 在我们之后是200辆坦克 50辆装甲车
The route is well guarded. Behind us are 200 tanks, 50 armoured cars
还有500挺机枪
and 500 machine-guns.
- 很好 - 很好
- Good. - Good.
我们准备好出发了吗?
Are we ready to start?
- 是的 - 是的
- Yes. - Yes.
先生们
Gentlemen.
Schultz 我很高兴你又回来同我们并肩作战了
Schultz, I'm happy you're with us again.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们这是要去哪里?
Where are we going?
您要入侵Osterlich的啊
You're invading Osterlich.
他们来了
They're coming.
阁下
Your Excellency.
全世界都正等候您发表演说
The world awaits your words.
出什么事了?他看上去很奇怪
What's happened? He looks strange.
Schultz在这里做什么?
What's Schultz doing here?
已经被原谅了 我猜
Pardoned, I suppose.
Garbitsch先生
His Excellency Herr Garbitsch,
内务秘书 宣传部长...
Secretary of the Interior, Minister of Propaganda...
胜利是需要付出代价的
Victory shall come to the worthy.
今天 民主 自由平等
Today, democracy, liberty and equality
是用来愚弄人民的字眼
are words to fool the people.
没有国家能靠这些进步
No nation can progress with such ideas.
它们是我们前进道路上的障碍 因此 我们要废除它们
They stand in the way of action. Therefore, we abolish them.
未来 每个人将绝对服从的为自己的国家服务
In the future, each man will serve the state with absolute obedience.
谁要是胆敢拒绝就得小心了!
Let him who refuses beware!
所有犹太人和非雅利安人的公民资格将被剥夺
Citizenship will be taken away from all Jews and non-Aryans.
他们是劣等的 因此还是国家的敌人
They are inferior and therefore enemies of the state.
憎恨 鄙视他们是所有真正雅利安人的职责
It is the duty of all true Aryans to hate and despise them.
这个国家被并入Tomainian帝国
This nation is annexed to the Tomainian Empire,
人民将会遵守我们伟大的领袖
and the people will obey the laws bestowed on us by our great leader,
Tomainia的独裁者 Osterlich的征服者 赐予我们的法律
the Dictator of Tomainia, the conqueror of Osterlich,
未来统治世界的皇帝!
the future Emperor of the World!
你一定得照着念
You must speak.
我办不到
I can't.
你必须 这是我们的唯一的希望
You must. It's our only hope.
希望...
Hope...
对不起 但我不想成为什么皇帝
I'm sorry, but I don't want to be an emperor.
那不是我的事情
That's not my business.
我不想统治或征服任何人
I don't want to rule or conquer anyone.
我想帮助每个人:
I should like to help everyone:
犹太人 非犹太人 黑人 白人
Jew, gentile, black man, white.
我们要彼此帮助 人类就应该那样
We all want to help one another. Human beings are like that.
我们要幸福的生活 而不是悲惨的
We want to live by each other's happiness, not misery.
我们不希望彼此憎恨
We don't want to hate one another.
在这个世界上
In this world,
土地是富足的 它能养活每一个人
the good earth is rich and can provide for everyone.
生活本可以是自由且美好的
The way of life can be free and beautiful
但是我们迷失了方向
but we have lost the way.
贪婪侵蚀了人们的灵魂
Greed has poisoned men's souls,
用憎恨阻隔了世界
has barricaded the world with hate,
我们一步步走向血腥
has goose-stepped us into bloodshed.
我们飞速发展 但是同时又自我封闭
We have developed speed but have shut ourselves in.
工业时代让我们物欲横流
Machinery has left us in want.
我们的知识让我们玩世不恭 我们的智慧让我们冷酷无情
Our knowledge has made us cynical, our cleverness, hard and unkind.
我们考虑得太多而感知得太少
We think too much and feel too little.
除了机器我们更需要人性
More than machinery we need humanity.
除了智慧我们更需要仁慈和礼貌
More than cleverness we need kindness and gentleness.
没有这些品格 生活将充满暴力 一切将不复存在...
Without these qualities, life will be violent and all will be lost...
飞机和收音机让我们彼此靠得更近
The aeroplane and radio have brought us closer.
这些发明呼唤人类的良知
These inventions cry out for the goodness in man,
呼唤全世界的手足情谊 让我们团结在一起
cry out for universal brotherhood, for the unity of us all.
现在我的声音传到数以百万的
Even now my voice is reaching millions,
数以百万的绝望的男人 女人和孩子们的耳朵里
millions of despairing men, women and children,
被那些在暴政制度下痛苦折磨的受难者
victims of a system that makes men torture
和无端入狱的人们的听到
and imprison innocent people.
我要对那些能够听到我讲话的人们说 不要绝望!
To those who can hear me I say, do not despair.
我们正经受的悲惨遭遇不过是那些畏惧人类进步的
The misery upon us is but the passing of greed,
贪婪的人所承受的痛苦
the bitterness of men who fear the way of human progress.
人们间憎恨将会过去 独裁者也会消亡
The hate of men will pass, and dictators die,
被他们夺走的权力将会重新回到人民的手中
and the power they took will return to the people.
只要人类没有灭亡自由之火就永不会熄灭
So long as men die liberty will never perish.
士兵们 不要替那些畜生们卖命
Soldiers, don't give yourselves to brutes,
他们鄙视你们 奴役你们
men who despise you, enslave you,
操纵你们的生命 告诉你该想什么 感觉什么
regiment your lives, tell you what to think and feel,
他们把你们当牛一样训练为的只是拿你们去当炮灰
who drill you, treat you like cattle and use you as cannon fodder.
不要把自己的命运交给给这些人
Don't give yourselves to these men,
这些像机器一样思想机械毫无感情的人
machine men with machine minds mand machine hearts.
你们不是机器 你们不是牛 你们是人!
You are not machines, you are not cattle, you are men!
你们每个人的心中有着人性的爱
You have the love of humanity in you.
不要憎恨 只有那些没有人爱和邪恶的人才会憎恨
Don't hate. Only the unloved and the unnatural hate.
士兵们 不要为奴役而战斗 要为了自由而战斗!
Soldiers, don't fight for slavery, fight for liberty!
圣徒路加说过 "上帝的国就就在人间"
St Luke says, "The Kingdom of God is within man. "
不在一个人也不是在一群人中 而是在所有的人中 就在你们之中!
Not in one man nor a group of men, but in all men. In you!
你们有能力创造机器
You have the power to create machines,
有能力去创造快乐
the power to create happiness.
你们有能力使生活自由而美好
You have the power to make this life free and beautiful,
把生活当作一场美妙的冒险
to make this life a wonderful adventure.
以民主的名义 让我们使用这种能力吧
In the name of democracy, let us use that power.
让我们联合起来 为创造一个崭新的世界而奋斗
Let us all unite, let us fight for a new world,
在这个世界人们将不会失业
a world that will give men a chance to work,
它会给青年人更好的未来 老人也老有所养
that will give youth a future and old age security.
那些畜生们对我们承诺过的
Promising these things, brutes have risen.
全都是谎言!他们没有实现那些诺言 永远都不会!
But they lie! They do not fulfil that promise. They never will!
独裁者使自己享受了自由却奴役其他人
Dictators free themselves but they enslave the people.
现在 让我们为实现那个诺言而斗争吧!
Now let us fight to fulfil that promise!
让我们为了自由的世界而斗争 为了废除国界而斗争
Let us fight to free the world, to do away with national barriers
为了驱除贪婪 憎恨和狭隘而斗争
to do away with greed, with hate and intolerance.
让我们为一个公正世界而斗争
Let us fight for a world of reason,
一个科学和进步将会为全体人类创造幸福的世界
a world where science and progress will lead to the happiness of all.
士兵们 以民主的名义
Soldiers, in the name of democracy,
让我们联合起来!
let us unite!
你能听到我吗?
can you hear me?
无论你在哪里 抬起头来 Hannah
Wherever you are, look up, Hannah.
乌云正在散去 阳光正穿破乌云
The clouds are lifting, the sun is breaking through.
我们正在从黑暗中走出来
We are coming out of the darkness
走进一个新的世界
into a new world,
一个更友好的世界
a kindlier world,
在那里人们将不会有憎恨和贪婪
where men will rise above their hate, their greed
残忍
and their brutality.
抬头看吧 Hannah
Look up, Hannah.
人类的灵魂插上了翅膀
The soul of man has been given wings.
他正飞入彩虹之中
He is flying into the rainbow,
飞入希望之光 飞向未来
into the light of hope, into the future,
光辉的未来属于你
the glorious future that belongs to you,
属于我 属于我们所有的人
to me and to all of us.
看啊 Hannah 看啊!
Look up, Hannah. Look up!
你听到了吗?
Did you hear that?
听啊...
Listen...